<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>That MLOps Guy</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on That MLOps Guy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>That MLOps Guy</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I replaced Homebrew and asdf with Devbox</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/posts/devbox/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/posts/devbox/</guid><description>In the last years, I used a combination of homebrew and asdf to manage some developer tools (eg. terraform, hadolint, ShellCheck, &amp;hellip;)
Recently I discovered devbox, a wrapper around NixOS package manager.
First install Devbox:
curl -fsSL https://get.jetify.com/devbox | bash Now, everytime I initialize a new project, instead of installing asdf plugins and declare it on .tool-versions, I just add the dependencies on devbox.json on the root of each project. First I run</description></item><item><title>Setup SSH keys from multiple Git accounts</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/posts/multiple-git-servers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/posts/multiple-git-servers/</guid><description>I generally create new SSH keys for each separate git server using the following setup:
ssh-keygen -t ed25519 -a 100 Unfortunately, Git doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide an option for what keys to use, you have to configure this in the ~/.ssh/config file:
# Personal account Host github.com HostName ssh.github.com IdentityFile ~/.ssh/id_ed25519_github User git # Company account Host gitcompany Hostname ssh.github.com User git IdentityFile ~/.ssh/id_ed25519_github_company Host private.git.server.com PreferredAuthentications publickey IdentityFile ~/.ssh/key_file_for_this Starting from git version 2.</description></item><item><title>Manage dotfiles with GNU Stow</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/posts/gnu-stow/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/posts/gnu-stow/</guid><description>I use GNU stow to manage all the important dotfiles.
Instructions Create a repo called dotfiles in your $HOME directory Recreate the directory structure for the files you want to manage as subdir(s) of that directory. mkdir -p ~/.dotfiles/bash mv ~/.bashrc ~/.bash_logout ~/.dotfiles/bash cd ~/.dotfiles stow bash Stow will create symlink for each file.
.bashrc -&amp;gt; dotfiles/bash/.bashrc Don´t forget to add this file to your git repo. Commit and push to remote and your done.</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a python developer by trade, so let&amp;rsquo;s say hello in python!
print(&amp;#34;Hello World&amp;#34;) This blog will be my little space of the internet where I can share what I feel I want to.
I&amp;rsquo;ll mostly write about tech stuff, but I won&amp;rsquo;t shut the door to any other subjects.
Any feedback is highly appreciated!
This concludes my first post of #100DaysToOffload.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hello there! I&amp;rsquo;m a random tech guy shouting into the void on the internet.
This is the place where I share my thoughts and notes about things that I’m excited about and working on and hope to connect with people having a similar mindset. I’d love to hear from you!
👋 About Me I&amp;rsquo;m a GNU/Linux user, a big advocate for the Free Software and the IndieWeb movements.
I have worked for 3+ years as Data Scientist, eventually finding my true calling in DevOps and MLOps.</description></item><item><title>Blogroll</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/blogroll/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/blogroll/</guid><description>Blogrolls are lists of other blogs that bloggers recommend to their readers.
Blogs This is a list of all the personal blogs I’m reading:
Drew DeVault danluu.com Daniel Stenberg Cheapskate&amp;rsquo;s Guide Krebs on Security Daring Fireball Jeff Geerling rinzewind.org Chris Wellons Julia Evans Cory Doctorow Aral Balkan Robert Heaton Security &amp;amp; Privacy Evaluations Dhole Moments sizeof(cat) Do the Math Mike Gerwitz Michael Durkan Find more blogs at blogroll.org and ooh.directory or search for feeds using feedle.</description></item><item><title>Bookmarks</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/bookmarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/bookmarks/</guid><description>Here’s a filtered selection of my personal bookmarks.
Each of the following articles and essays stuck with me after I first read it, becoming part of how I look at the world. I’m listing them here in one place so it’s easier for me to find them.
Aristotle - How to live a good life Ignorance vs. stupidity</description></item><item><title>Books</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/books/</guid><description>The Best Books I read I have gathered here the few books I consider to be masterpieces.
Nicomachean Ethics by Aristotle Enchiridion by Epictetus Skin in the Game: Hidden Asymmetries in Daily Life by Nassim Nicholas Taleb Limits to Growth: The 30-Year Update by Meadows, Donella H.; Randers, Jorgen; Meadows, Dennis L. Thinking in systems: a primer by Donella H Meadows, Diana Wright Energy and Civilization: A History by Vaclav Smil Atomic Habits: An Easy &amp;amp; Proven Way to Build Good Habits &amp;amp; Break Bad Ones by James Clear</description></item><item><title>Links</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/links/</guid><description>Here are some sites I enjoy and would recommend.
Suckless: Software that sucks less Cat-v.org cli.club Use plain text email e-mail is not SMS No hello: please don&amp;rsquo;t say just hello in chat. Join the club. conventional comments Small web clubs: no-js, 250Kb, 512Kb, 1Mb</description></item><item><title>Now</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/now/</guid><description>What I’m doing now.
This is a now page, and if you have your own site, you should make one, too.
Life I need to improve quality of life, so I’m trying to:
Reading more books. (re)Focusing on my wellbeing and a healthy lifestyle. Journaling my life. Work and Life Breaking things as a Cloud/DevOps/MLOps engineer. Remote work, work anywhere.</description></item><item><title>Quotes</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/quotes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/quotes/</guid><description>Random quotes collected from various sources
“Anyone who believes that exponential growth can go on forever in a finite world is either a madman or an economist.” Kenneth Boulding
“It is difficult to get a man to understand something, when his salary depends on his not understanding it.” Upton Sinclair
“The only function of economic forecasting is to make astrology look respectable.” John Kenneth Galbraith
“Growth for the sake of growth is the ideology of the cancer cell.</description></item><item><title>Subscribe</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/subscribe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/subscribe/</guid><description>Subscribe to My Blog You can subscribe to this blog using RSS/Atom feeds, you can grab the feed from here.
If you don’t know what is RSS and/or Atom, read on aboutfeeds.com how these RSS web feeds work in detail.</description></item><item><title>Uses</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/uses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/uses/</guid><description>Inspired by many pages out there, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together this page that covers some parts of my setup.
Development IDE: VSCode. I also use Emacs for the excellent org-mode. Terminal emulator: URxvt shell: zsh with oh-my-zsh Terminal multiplexer: Tmux I also use various terminal utilities and CLI tools that I use for scripting and just general shell surfing. Some of them that I want to give a shout-out to, in rapid fire:</description></item><item><title>Where</title><link>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/where/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatmlopsguy.github.io/where/</guid><description>This is my where page 📍, showing where in this world I am right now.
Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m in the Portugal 🇵🇹.
A where page is a place on the web where you can let others know about your current location. Read here about the where page movement.</description></item></channel></rss>